# **Scott Bennett**

scott.bennett@twc.com • scottbennett.dev • In scott-bennett • 859-653-0627 Cincinnati, OH

#### **SUMMARY**

Extensive experience in the Computer/Electronics Industry, including positions as Operations Manager, Project Manager, Sales Manager, Technical Support Specialist, Repair Technician and iOS/Swift Programmer. Strong entrepreneurial skills developed as an owner/operator of a computer sales, service and design company.

### **SKILLS**

Programming: Swift, Objective-C, Python, C

**Business:** Strategic planning, cost reduction and containment, global and strategic sourcing, troubleshooting and problem solving, inventory control, sales, technical support **Technical:** Project Manager, Mobile Development

### **EXPERIENCE**

Lambda School, CA 2019 - 2020

Teaching Assistant

Taught iOS/Swift using example projects to show programming concepts to students remotely.

Team Leader

Assisted students during training, graded projects, helped with debugging and answered coding questions. *Project Leader* 

Led/Assisted a group of students to complete a web/mobile application.

### Imagine Communications (Digital Rapids), Erlanger, KY

2007 - 2017

Operations Manager

Manufactured and supported high-end custom turnkey servers used in the video distribution industry.

Responsible for Quality Control for hardware assembly and software installations.

Maintained inventory control of thousands of complex computer system parts.

Performed world wide shipping and logistics of completed products.

## **Expert Services, Florence, KY**

1989 - 2007

Owner/Operator

Operated a retail computer sales/service company specializing in graphics and video production.

Managed sales people and assembly/repair technicians.

Setup and executed support contracts for SMB customers.

Created partnerships with foreign manufacturers to distribute products in the US.

Managed development and took to market multiple consumer products.

Performed marketing activities.

## Digital Processing Systems, Florence, KY

1996 - 1999

Project Manager

Successfully launched multiple products for the consumer/professional video market.

Technical Support

Supported full line of consumer and professional digital video products worldwide.

### **EDUCATION**

### Lambda School

Completed an intensive 6+ month Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy that provided an immersive hands-on curriculum with a track focused on iOS. Through this program I:

- Approached all coding challenges using pair programming.
- Gained hands-on experience with customer user interfaces, code quality, design patterns and testing, to ultimately deploy an app store ready app.
- Completed an iOS deep dive into: Objective-C, Media, and other Apple platforms.
- Engaged Python, algorithms, data structures, graphs, C, and other operating systems.

University of Louisville, J.B. Speed School of Engineering, Louisville, KY Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering

### **SOFTWARE PROJECTS**

FlexiScore - Available in App Store SpeakView - Individual project Golf Card Score Keeper - Individual project ToolDB - Individual project Sentiment Bot - Team project Replate - Project leader WunderList 2.0 - Project leader FoodieFun - Project Leader

## **ACTIVITIES**

Taught programming class for Boy Scout Merit Badge Challenge. Adult leader for several Boy Scout high adventure trips, including hiking and sailing. Golf, SCUBA diving, woodworking, swimming, hiking, camping.